<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Dr. D&#39;s Data Science</title>
<link>https://drddatascience.com/blog.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://drddatascience.com/blog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Public Safety Data Science by Dr. Tony Dunsworth</description>
<generator>quarto-1.6.39</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Thanks and Thoughts</title>
  <dc:creator>Tony Dunsworth</dc:creator>
  <link>https://drddatascience.com/posts/20241223/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Well, the site is now live, thanks to Ionos’ technical support. I have to compliment the person who followed up with me today. He helped me get everything taken care of and get the site live and available for you to see. It’s nice to go from working to build it to seeing it out there where everyone else can see it and we can go on this journey together.</p>
<p>I also want to thank <a href="https://beamilz.com">Beartiz Milz</a> for writing an awesome <a href="https://beamilz.com/posts/2022-06-05-creating-a-blog-with-quarto/en/">tutorial</a> that helped me turn my limited knowledge of Quarto and my comfort with R into a website and blog to promote my work in 911 data science. I’m also using her tutorial to build a blog as a vehicle for new reports in my PSAP.</p>
<p>For the last 14 years, I’ve written reports for two different PSAPs and felt like my reports have not illuminated everything that the data has to offer. The weekly and monthly reports have been things I’ve been asked to develop. However, there is always so much more in the data which could be important. Can we use knowledge about what days and hours are busiest change how we schedule telecommunicators? Can we see training oportunities by focusing on how long it takes us to process specific call types? Are there hidden correlations in the data that we’ve been missing because we don’t see them? I’ve thought of these questions forever. Now that I’ve finished my doctorate, I want to spend the time investigating these and other questions.</p>
<p>I think that I can build templates that I can share with other interested PSAPs and we can start building better reporting systems which can, by being served as dashboards and websites, make the reports more responsive while automating the delivery. I want to mke things easier for everyone.</p>
<p>I updated my <a href="https://medium.com/@trdunsworth">Medium</a> site with an annoucement that this blog exists and has become active. I’ve also updated <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/tonyrdunsworth">LinkedIn</a> with a link to that <a href="https://medium.com/@trdunsworth/new-blog-new-goals-same-ol-me-107d3dec8cf6">article</a> and invited my friends and contacts there to add comments and ask questions that can turn into blog posts. I will post this article there too, once I’ve published it.</p>
<p>So, this is where this post ends. I will post something new in a couple of days. I’m going to challenge myself to add some code in the next one to see what happens. I have a couple of ideas in mind.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>news</category>
  <category>thoughts</category>
  <category>reports</category>
  <guid>https://drddatascience.com/posts/20241223/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Start of a New Blog</title>
  <dc:creator>Tony Dunsworth</dc:creator>
  <link>https://drddatascience.com/posts/startingpoint/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>This is, for me, a starting point post. I am just starting to develop this site, including this blog, as a way to do several things at once. First and foremost, I want to document my work in public safety communications data science. This is a turning point in my career, transitioning from back-end administration of dispatch systems to data analytics and data science.</p>
<p>Another part of this blog will discuss things I find interesting in tech, especially when it comes to data. For example, I have been working more and more in Python lately and finding tools that I enjoy using because they make my work easier. The top three of late are <a href="https://github.com/astral-sh/uv">uv</a>, <a href="https://duckdb.org/">DuckDB</a>, and <a href="https://fireducks-dev.github.io/">FireDucks</a>. Over time, I will add Jupyter notebooks here so I can document my work with these and other tools.</p>
<p>I also want to learn more about <a href="https://julialang.org/">Julia</a>. So I might experiment with it in notebooks as well here and there and document the experience. However, most of the code that you see here will be in R, because it was the first language that I learned and the one that I feel most comfortable with. That will present its own challenge because many forecasting libraries that I have worked with are only expressed in Python.</p>
<p>There will be some tutorials as I write more and I get more comfortable with writing here and updating the blog and the site. Most of those are going to be geared towards public safety communications. I work with <a href="https://nena.org">NENA</a> on several technical committees and part of that work, for me, focuses on bringing advanced analytics to PSAPs across the country. I also speak a few times a year on this and other topics. I will start blogging about what I have presented after the presentations are done. It will be good review.</p>
<p>I am also fascinated with generating synthetic data for analyses. Right now, I’ve been working with <a href="https://mostly.ai/">Mostly.ai</a> to generate synthetic data for my research work. Due to the nature of the work that I do in centres, I use synthetic data for my presentations and my tutorials. My goal is to work with other libraries to create more realistic data for research purposes. I know that I will write about that in future posts. I’m looking forward to having fun with that exploration.</p>
<p>Many of my posts will be found on my <a href="https://medium.com/@trdunsworth">Medium</a> page. Some of the tutorials may also be found, in the future, on my <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/tonyrdunsworth">LinkedIn</a>. However, I will point my audience here over time because there will be posts here that don’t exist other places so I can promote this place as my prefered publication venue.</p>
<p>Well, I think that this is a good start as a pre-launch blog post.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>news</category>
  <guid>https://drddatascience.com/posts/startingpoint/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
